<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Personal Development on Charisse Writes</title>
    <link>https://www.charisseysabel.com/categories/personal-development/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Personal Development on Charisse Writes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 02 Sep 2017 09:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.charisseysabel.com/categories/personal-development/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>3 Things to Keep in Mind When Starting a Blog</title>
      <link>https://www.charisseysabel.com/post/2017-09-02-3-things-to-keep-in-mind-when-starting-a-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Sep 2017 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.charisseysabel.com/post/2017-09-02-3-things-to-keep-in-mind-when-starting-a-blog/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes we just need to remind ourselves why we want to dive into the world of blogging.
3 things, here we go.
What is your goal? It&amp;rsquo;s important to keep in mind why you want to start / started blogging in the first place. I firmly believe that this will help you keep going during those times when you feel like you want to quit.
My purpose for this blog is to be able to explain things to myself — as selfish as that sounds.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Goals without Deadlines</title>
      <link>https://www.charisseysabel.com/post/2017-07-15-goals-without-deadlines/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jul 2017 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.charisseysabel.com/post/2017-07-15-goals-without-deadlines/</guid>
      <description>Have you ever failed to reach a goal? Like so many other people out there, I too, have set a goal for myself and in one way or another, failed to reach that goal on a set date.
This is a blogpost outlining the talk that I have given at Women Who Code Berlin.
So what exactly are goals? People have different definitions about it but for me, goals are the things or the outcomes that we want to achieve in life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Being Productive</title>
      <link>https://www.charisseysabel.com/post/2017-03-06-on-being-productive/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2017 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.charisseysabel.com/post/2017-03-06-on-being-productive/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve read a lot of articles about productivity. I like to read them because they&amp;rsquo;re motivating, promising satisfaction and a great sense of achievement. Sometimes they even introduce new apps or new methods, which are interesting discoveries on its own.
But a couple weeks back, I was looking at my to-do list and I realized that I had &amp;rdquo;so much to do&amp;rdquo; but at the end of the day, I still didn&amp;rsquo;t feel productive.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>